up0.net 2006-07-01

# Privacy policy - EmailLabs - Uptilt

|  | 

**Privacy Policy  
**  
The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for the Uptilt and Email Labs websites. Please note that this policy in no way supersedes, replaces or complements the privacy policies of our clients (see Client Data below)

**EU Safe Harbor**

Uptilt adheres to the [European Union Safe Harbor](http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/sh_overview.html) principles as set forth by the [United States Department of Commerce](http://web.ita.doc.gov/safeharbor/SHList.nsf/2ff3ed061f49424085256967004eddf0/0654227f01502aac85256ed300787c92!OpenDocument) regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from the European Union. Our privacy practices are self-certified as part of the [U.S. Commerce Department's Safe Harbor Program](http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/SafeHarborInfo.htm).

**EmailLabs (Uptilt) Privacy Notice**

The Uptilt site offers several opportunities for visitors to register for free information, seminars or demonstration copies of our software, and for assistance in evaluating our software and services. These registration forms are often linked to Uptilt mailing lists and require users to give contact information (such as name and e-mail address). We use this contact information to send users information about our company and its products and services. The information is also used to contact site visitors by e-mail for marketing purposes if they have granted permission to us to send it to them on the mailing list form (or other forms on our web site), and for administrative purposes such as time and location of seminars. Users may also be contacted by phone or postal mail for marketing purposes. Any financial information collected is shared with our credit card processor to bill users for Uptilt software, and is stored by our credit card processor and Uptilt 

We use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server, and to administer our Web site. Your IP address is also used to gather broad, personally non-identifiable demographic information, such as which countries our site visitors come from. This web site does not currently use cookies, but it may do so in the future. If so, cookies may be used to correlate previously supplied information about you for personalization and tracking purposes. 

The Uptilt web site contains links to other sites. Uptilt is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such web sites and recommends that viewers check the privacy policies of other sites to be aware of how your information is being used.

**Choice / Access**

Uptilt provides users the opportunity to opt-in and opt-out of receiving e-mail communications from us. This is made available during sign-up for our e-mail lists and in e-mail messages delivered from Uptilt Systems. Users requesting Uptilt e-mail communications may update, amend, or delete personal information by following the Profile Update links present in every Uptilt e-mail communication.

For any list managed by Uptilt, users can use the link in the footer of most e-mail messages. Alternatively, users can reply to an e-mail message according to the instructions at the bottom of the message.

**Third-Party Sharing**

Information collected as referenced above is not shared or transferred to third parties except with your express permission or where required by law.   
**  
Client Data**

Uptilt provides online marketing services and products to its clients. These services include customer database management and analysis, e-mail delivery, e-mail tracking and web site tracking. For all clients, Uptilt is contractually bound to keep customer data private and prevented from sharing data across multiple clients. For example, if one of our client's customers has two e-mail addresses, and these addresses are stored in our database, we may not share this fact with another client, even if the second client has the same customer has the first client. The example below illustrates this. Client A and Client B both share the customer John Doe. Client A has two email addresses for John Doe, but Client B does not because Client B has not gathered that information.

| 

**Client A**

| 

**Client B**  
  
---|---  
| **Name** | **Email Addresses**  
---|---  
John Doe | JohnDoe@someaddress.com  
JohnDoe@anotheraddress.com  
| **Name** | **Email Addresses**  
---|---  
John   
Doe | JohnDoe@someaddress.com  
  
Uptilt's services sometimes use cookies to help our clients better analyze the success of their email and other online marketing campaigns. The cookies we serve are often correlated with individually identifiable information, but this information is not shared with anyone other than the client. As with the email example above, this data is not shared across multiple clients.

_Uptilt is not responsible for its clients' privacy policies and makes no representations about their accuracy. If you have questions about our clients' practices, we recommend you check their privacy policies and/or contact them directly._ **Security** **  
**  
Uptilt uses industry standard security technologies and processes, such as secure sockets layer, encryption, and a physically protected data center, to protect your data. 

**Enforcement**

Uptilt privacy practices are self-certified as part of the U.S. Commerce Department's Safe Harbor Program. For more information please go to Safe Harbor Program website. 

******Notice of Change** _ **  
**_ Uptilt reserves the right to change its privacy policy at any time. Notifications of changes to our privacy practices will occur through one or more of the following communications: 

| Posting of a message on the www.Uptilt.com home page   
---|---  
  
| Users voluntarily viewing the privacy statement for periodic changes
